<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The appointments of Edward Russell, Esq; now Earl of Orford, when he was Admiral of the Blue, and Admiral of the Fleet</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1705</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A75524</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3582A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC T22337</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99897881</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99897881</idno>
            <idno type="VID">170918</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A75524)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 170918)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2523:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The appointments of Edward Russell, Esq; now Earl of Orford, when he was Admiral of the Blue, and Admiral of the Fleet</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1705]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History, Naval --  Stuarts, 1603-1714 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:170918:1"/>
            <head>The Appointments of <hi>EDWARD RUSSELL,</hi> Eſq; now Earl of <hi>Orford,</hi> when he was Admiral of the Blue, and Admiral of the Fleet.</head>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="label"> </cell>
                     <cell role="label">l.</cell>
                     <cell role="label">s.</cell>
                     <cell role="label">d.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>IN the Years 1689 and 1690, he was Treaſurer of the Navy at 3000 <hi>l.</hi> Commiſſioner of the Admiralty at 1000 <hi>l</hi> and Admiral of the Blue at 1277 <hi>l.</hi> 10 <hi>s.</hi> and Table-Money 365 <hi>l.</hi> tho' he was not at Sea; the whole for each Year</cell>
                     <cell>5642</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>In the Years 1691 and 1692, he was Treaſurer of the Navy at 3000 <hi>l.</hi> Firſt Commiſſioner of the Admiralty at 1000 <hi>l.</hi> and Admiral of the Fleet at 2555 <hi>l.</hi> The whole for each Year</cell>
                     <cell>6555</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>He had the Year 1691, to make his Equipage, the Grant of <hi>Suffolk-Street,</hi> which was valued at</cell>
                     <cell>18000</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>He had the Year 1692, to make his Equipage, a Grant out of the Under Woods of the Forreſt of <hi>Deane</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>10000</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>In the Years 1694 and 1695, he was Treaſurer of the Navy at 3000 <hi>l.</hi> Firſt Commiſſioner of the Admiralty 1000 <hi>l.</hi> and Admiral of the Fleet at 2555 <hi>l.</hi> The whole for each Year</cell>
                     <cell>6555</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>And for his Equipage at his going to Sea, a Grant of the Ground-Rents of the Houſe behind the Pay-Office in <hi>Broadſtreet,</hi> valued at a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout.</cell>
                     <cell>10000</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Beſides, for the Years 1696 and 1697, he was continued in all the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid Employments; as alſo Admiral of the Fleet, with Table-Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> tho' he was not at Sea; and Sir <hi>George Rook</hi>'s Commiſſion as Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miral and Commander of the Fleet, bore date the 28th of <hi>April</hi> 1696; ſo that, for theſe Two Years, he was paid as a Supernumerary Admiral of the Fleet, which Sum is</cell>
                     <cell>5110</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>He paſs'd his Contingent Account for Nineteen thouſand Pounds by <hi>Sign Manual,</hi> the Navy Board having refus'd to paſs it for want of Regular Vouchers, and ſome extraordinary Articles, as the bringing to Account the gratuity he gave to the Perſon that brought him the Jewel from the King of <hi>Spain,</hi> that was valued at 7000 Piſtoles, and the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thecary's Bill, and Fees that he gave to the Phyſician that attended him during his Sickneſs at <hi>Alicant,</hi> hire of his Houſe, Coach-hire, Expences on the Road, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And paſs'd his Victualling Account of Eighty thouſand Pounds, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Regular Vouchers, by Privy-Seal.</p>
            <p>And had paid to him by Sir <hi>Martin Weſtcombe,</hi> Commiſſioner of the Prizes at <hi>Cadiz,</hi> on the account of Prizes, about the Sum of Ninety thouſand Pounds, which has never yet been accounted for to the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick.</p>
            <p>Without taking notice of his laying the <hi>Genoueze</hi> Captains in Irons till they had bought their Paſſes.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:170918:2"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
